RG 043, Board of Parole
Connecticut State Library
Board of Parole records
1933-1991
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Board of Parole
9 cubic feet
The Board of Parole made release decisions based upon the likelihood that released prisoners would remain at liberty without violating the terms and conditions of their parole agreement and supervised those who are granted parole.
RG043
2003-023
Historical Note
The 1903 Indeterminate Sentencing Law allowed each of the state prisions to authorize their own paroles. In 1957, a three member Board of Parole was created to replace the State Prison Board of Directors as the paroling authority. On July 1, 1968, the Department of Correction was established with an autonomous, single State Board of Parole, to replace the former three separate boards of parole. On July 1, 2001, the State Board of Parole was replaced by Connecticut Board of Pardons and Paroles.
See also the.
Scope and Content
This record group contains minutes of meetings, public information release logs, and
"A Report to the Legislature of the State of Connecticut on Capital Punishment and the Administration of Homicide Laws".
Arrangement
Series 1. Minutes, 1933-1991, 8 cubic feet
Series 2. Administrative Records, 1960, 1980-1989, 1 cubic foot
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. Board of Parole
Subjects:
Connecticut. Board of Parole -- Records and correspondence; Parole -- Connecticut; Criminal justice, Administration of -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Logs (records); Minutes; Reports
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Series 1. Minutes, 1933-1991; 8 cubic feet
  - 1933 January-1937 June, 1944-1959, 6 binders (Box 1)
    Remainder of 1937 and part of 1938 missing.
  - 1960-1966, 7 binders (Box 2)
  - 1967 January-1971 June, 7 binders (Box 3)
  - 1971-1974, 7 binders (Box 4)
  - 1975-1976, 1978, 6 binders + loose papers (Box 5)
    No minutes for 1977. Duplicate copy of minutes for 1978.
  - 1979-1981, 5 binders (Box 6)
    Duplicate set of minutes for 1981 June-December.
  - 1982-1987, 4 binders (Box 7)
  - 1988-1991, 3 binders (Box 8)
- Series 2. Administrative Records, 1960; 1980-1989; 1 cubic foot
  - Public information release logs, 1980-1989; 4 binders (Box 9)
  - "A Report to the Legislature of the State of Connecticut on Capital Punishment and the Administration of Homicide Laws", Carroll W. Brewster, Yale University Law School, 1960 June 1, thermo fax copy, very brittle and browned, 1 binder (Box 9)